Hiroki Watanabe

Keio University Phone: +81-45-563-1141

Graduate School of Science and Technology Email: nelio@inl.ics.keio.ac.jp

3-14-1 Hiyoshi, Kouhoku-ku, Homepage: https://neglio.github.io

Yokohama, Kanagawa, JAPAN 223-8522

A computer science researcher with research interests in network architecture (especially in edge computing), protocol stack, and SDN/NFV. Intersts in not only network system but also in all layers of computer system such as hardware design, OS, middleware, and userland applications. Experience in developing a session layer protocol in userland providing applications with rich communication paths (multipath, DTN, middlemox, and etc.) in C language and in developing a set of middleware for distributed edge cloud computing in C language.

EDUCATION

APR 2018 - Current Ph.D student in Engineering, Keio University, Japan

MAR 2018 M.E. degree in Engineering

from Keio University, Japan (GPA: 3.67/4)

Thesis: "Design and Implementation of A Communication Mechanism

for Application-level Service Chaining" | Advisor: Fumio Teraoka

MAR 2016 B.E. degree in Information and Computer Science

from Keio University, Japan (GPA: 3.81/4)

Thesis: "A Prototype Implementation of A Session Layer on New Generation Network Architecture: ZNA" | Advisor: Fumio Teraoka

EMPLOYMENT

MAR 2017 - Current | Research Assistant at IIJ Innovation Institute

Developing Software around LKL and MPTCP

Aug. 2016 - Sep. 2016 | Internship at Yahoo! Japan

Developing Cassandra at Data Platform Department

LANGUAGES

JAPANESE: Native Speaker
ENGLISH: Good Command
GERMAN: Basic Communication

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Application development using C/Python/Go Network operation (routers, L2/L3 switches, servers, etc.)

PUBLICATIONS

Journal Articles

1. Hiroki Watanabe, Takao Kondo, Kunitake Kaneko, Fumio Teraoka, "Inserting Layer-5 to Provide

Applications with Richer Functions through Common API," *IEICE Transactions on Communications*, Vol. E101-B, No.9. (will be published)

Proceedings

1. <u>H. Watanabe</u>, T. Kondo, K. Kaneko and F. Teraoka, "Separating Communication Policies and Mechanisms to Make Protocol Layering Clearer," 2017 26th International Conference on Computer Communication and Networks (ICCCN), Vancouver, BC, 2017, pp. 1–9. (Acceptance Rate: 27%)

Workshops

- 1. Kazuki Hayashi, <u>Hiroki Watanabe</u>, Takao Kondo, Fumio Teraoka, "Automatic Construction Mechanism for Experimental Virtual Network Considering Network Topology," *IEICE Tech. Rep.*, vol. 117, no. 472, IA2017-73, pp. 37-42, March 2018.
- 2. Yutaro Hayakawa, <u>Hiroki Watanabe</u>, Kazuya Okada, "clnfv: A Container-based Lightweight NFV Architecture," *IEICE Tech. Rep.*, vol. 117, no. 303, NS2017-111, pp. 1-6, November 2017.
- 3. <u>Hiroki Watanabe</u>, Takao Kondo, Kunitake Kaneko, Fumio Teraoka, "Underway-aware Virtual Network Construction Infrastructure," *The Eighteenth Workshop on Internet Technology (WIT2017)*, Matsuyama, June 2017.
- 4. Daiki Mitake, <u>Hiroki Watanabe</u>, Kunitake Kaneko, Fumio Teraoka, "Extention of Layer-5 for DTN on ZNA, a New Generation Network Architecture," *IEICE Tech. Rep.*, vol. 116, no. 434, IA2016-89, pp. 61-66, January 2017.
- 5. <u>Hiroki Watanabe</u>, Kunitake Kaneko, Fumio Teraoka, "A Prototype Implementation of Session Layer on New Generation Network Architecture ZNA," *IPSJ SIG Tech. Rep. on the 78th National Convention of IPSJ*, vol. 2016, no. 1, pp. 81-83, March 2016.
- 6. <u>Hiroki Watanabe</u>, Kunitake Kaneko, Fumio Teraoka, "L5-path: A Session Layer Protocol on ZNA, a New Generation Network Architecture," *IEICE Tech. Rep.*, vol. 115, no. 482, IA2015-103, pp. 191-196, March 2016. (Student Incentive Award)
- 7. <u>Hiroki Watanabe</u>, Keigo Mizotani, Yusuke Hatori, Hiroyuki Chishiro, Nobuyuki Yamasaki, "A Low Latency Real-Time Execution with Interrupt Wake-up Structure," *IPSJ SIG Tech. Rep. on the Embedded System Symposium 2015*, pp. 531–543, October 2015.

AWARDS

1. "Student Incentive Award," IEICE-IA, March 2016.